A Finding Aid to the Heritage Gallery Records, 1944-2000, bulk 1960-1998, in the Archives of American Art AAA.herigall
Archives of American Art
Heritage Gallery records
bulk 1960-1998
1944-2000
AAA.herigall
Archives of American Art
13.8 Linear feet
The records of Los Angeles Heritage Gallery measure 13.8 linear feet and date from 1944-2000 with the bulk of the materials dating from 1960-1998. The majority of the collection consists of artists’ files containing a wide variety of materials documenting the gallery’s representation of its contemporary artists and gallery exhibitions, including biographical information, correspondence, and printed materials. About half of the artists’ files are related to artist Charles White. Gallery records also include business correspondence, business records and additional printed materials.
Heritage Gallery
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 3 series.
Series 1: Artists' Files, 1944-2000, bulk 1960-1998 (11.6 linear feet; Boxes 1-12, 15-16, OV 17)
Series 2: Business Correspondence and Records, 1945-1997 (1.6 linear feet; Boxes 12-13)
Series 3: Printed Material, 1960s-1990s (0.6 linear feet; Boxes 13-14, 16)
Biographical/Historical note
Founder Benjamin Horowitz (1912-2004) was born in New York City and moved to Hollywood shortly before the outbreak of World War II. He began a career as a writer of detective fiction but was interrupted by the draft. Horowitz opened Heritage Gallery in the early 1960s on La Cienega Boulevard in Los Angeles, California. His early dedication to African-American artists, chief among them Charles White to whom he gave more than 51 one-person exhibitions, distinguished the gallery.
Horowitz was the co-founder of the Art Dealers Association of California and also worked as an appraiser.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Heritage Gallery records were donated by Benjamin Horowitz, founder of the gallery, in two accessions in 1998 and 2000.
Related Archival Materials note
The Archives of American Art holds several collections related to Heritage Gallery and Benjamin Horowitz, including the William Gropper papers and the Charles Wilbert White papers. Also found in the Archives is an oral history interview with Benjamin Horowitz conducted by Molly Saltman as a part of "Art and Artists" interviews, 1965-1966.
Scope and Contents note
The records of Los Angeles Heritage Gallery measure 13.8 linear feet and date from 1944-2000 with the bulk of the materials dating from 1960-1998. The majority of the collection consists of artists’ files containing a wide variety of materials documenting the gallery’s representation of its contemporary artists and gallery exhibitions, including biographical information, correspondence, and printed materials. About half of the artists’ files are related to artist Charles White. Gallery records also include business correspondence, business records and additional printed materials.
The bulk of the collection are artists’ files which document the works and careers of Heritage Gallery artists through a wide variety of materials including biographical information, correspondence, scattered financial records, inventory lists and price lists, printed materials, and photographic materials. Especially rich are the folders of correspondence with Social Realist artist William Gropper, and materials related to artists José Clemente Orozco, David Alfaro Siqueiro, Moses Soyer and Raphael Soyer. Additionally, about half of the Artists’ Files are related to African-American artist Charles White, for whom Horowitz was the sole representative of his artwork, but also a personal friend to White and his family.
Business correspondence and records contain incoming and outgoing correspondence with clients and galleries regarding artwork sales, consignments and exhibition loans; contracts, many with artists and lithographers; biographical information about Benjamin Horowitz; and other day-to-day business records.
Printed material documents exhibitions held at Heritage Gallery through exhibition announcement, catalogs, clippings, and posters, as well as a handful of printed materials for exhibitions held at other galleries and museums.
Gropper, William, 1897-; Horowitz, Benjamin, 1912-; Orozco, José Clemente, 1883-1949; Siqueiros, David Alfaro; Soyer, Moses, 1899-1974; Soyer, Raphael, 1899-1987; White, Charles, 1918-1979; Art galleries, Commercial--California--Los Angeles
- Artists' Files, bulk 1960-1998; 1944-2000; Series 1; 11.6 Linear feet Boxes 1-12, 15-16, OV 17
  Scope and Contents note
  Artists’ files document the exhibitions and careers of the Heritage Gallery artists through biographies and background information; correspondence regarding artwork sales, consignments, exhibitions, and appraisals; clippings; exhibition announcements and catalogs; financial and accounting records; inventory and price lists; photographs and slides; and other records. Especially rich are the folders of correspondence with artist William Gropper.
  About half of the series are materials related to Charles White, documenting the Heritage Gallery’s sole representation of the artist, as well as the friendship between Horowitz, White, and White’s family. Materials include biographical information; correspondence in rough chronological order with clients, museums, and galleries regarding artwork sales, exhibitions, and loans; inventory lists; and voluminous printed material such as clippings, exhibition catalogs, press releases, and flyers.
  Arrangement note
  The folders are arranged alphabetically by artist’s last name; folders containing various artists are filed at the end of the series.
  - Adams, Ron, circa 1980s-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aron, Kalman, 1975-1977; 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bailey, Max, undated; 1962-circa 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Barnes, Ernie, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Oversized material housed in Box 16, Folder 1
  - Barthé, Richmond, 1976-1993 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Bejar, Feliciano, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Benjamin, Karl, circa 1980-1983; 1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bennett, Herbert, 1968-1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Berger, Pat, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Biberman, Edward, 1958-1981 (Box 1, Folder 12-14)
  - Biberman, Edward, Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Binder, Erwin, 1982-1991 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Blaisdell, Don, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Blanch, Arnold, 1968-1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Booth, Cameron, 1962-1972 (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
  - Briggs, Rod, 1965-1979 (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
  - Bruno, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bustion, Nathaniel, Jr., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Cabral, Flavio, 1990; 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Carbajal, Ricardo, 1974-1990s (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Cardona-Hine, Alvaro, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Casas, Fernando, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Chagall, Marc, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Cherkas, Constantine, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Clayberger, Samuel, 1988-1999 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Deutsch, Boris, circa 1990s (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Dimondstein, Mort, 1952; 1976; 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Dora, Miklos, Hungarian Artists [Laszlo Bod], 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Downs, Richard, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Eichler, Christina, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Engel, Jules, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Erlich, Ruth, circa 1994; 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Frame, Robert, 1966-1969; 1984 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Gardner, Tom, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Gershgoren, Milton, 1987; 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Gilien, Ted, 1968-1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Gojman, Ana, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Grayson, Marvin, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Gropper, William (Box 2)
    - Artwork Loans, Gifts and Exhibitions, 1977-1984; 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Book, circa 1980 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Book Manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1962; 1967-1992 (Box 2, Folder 9-16)
    - Inventory Appraisal, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - The Nation Magazine [photocopies], undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Payments, 1967-1986 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Printed Materials, 1962-1994 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Haimowitz, Herman, 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Hammersley, Frederick, 1959-1999 (Box 2, Folder 22-24)
  - Harmon, Sidney, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Hebald, Milton, 1971-1989 (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
  - Herschensohn, Arthur, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Hirschberger, Fritz, 1988-1999 (Box 3, Folder 2-5)
  - Hobbs, Fredric, 1975-1979; 1994 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Hockney, [David], 1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Homer, Winslow, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Hueter, James, 1961-1969 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
    Oversized material housed in Box 16, Folder 2
  - Hyman, Beverlye, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Jaffe, Bettye, 1993-1999 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Kanin, Michael, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Kantaroff, Maryon, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Kaplan, Samuel, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Karlin, Eugene, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Katz, Alan, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Khatchatrian, Rudolph, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Kim, Chung Sook, 1971-1977 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Kingman, Eduardo, 1957-1965 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Kissell, Theodora, 1965-1968 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Kistler, Lynton, 1970-1984 (Box 3, Folder 22-23)
  - Kocharian, Ruben, 1974; 1987-1996; 1976 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Kolosvary, Eva and Paul, 1973-1983; 1995-2000 (Box 3, Folder 25-26)
  - Kosa, Emil, Jr., 1989-1997 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Lacy, Ernest, 1960-2000 (Box 3, Folder 28-29)
  - Lacy, Ernest, Account Statements, 1961-1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Levine, Shirley, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Lutz, Dan, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Mancini, John, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Marin, John, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Marinoff, Elaine, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Mazière, Jacques, 1982-1985 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - McFee, Henry Lee, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Miles, Melinda, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Millier, Arthur, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Moholy-Nagy, László, 1970-1987 (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
  - Moore, Henry, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Morrow, Ken, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Moses, Grandma, 1984-1990 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Mugnaini, Joseph, 1967-1987 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Musgrave, Lee, 1979-1985 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - O'Keeffe, Georgia, Sunflower in Oval, 1994-1995; 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Olson, Meredith, 1986; 1961-1966 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Oñate, Michele de, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Orlando, John, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Orozco, José Clemente, 1944-1948; 1970s-1992 (Box 4, Folder 22-25)
  - Orozco, José Clemente, Exhibition Inventory, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Orozco, José Clemente, Museum, 1986-1991 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Orozco, José Clemente, Slides, circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 28-29)
  - Pajaud, William, 1988; 1968-1981 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Peterson, Roland, 1962; 1968 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Phillips, Barbara, 1962-1966 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Piper, Rose, 1990-1998 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Pippin, Horace, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Read, Claire, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Refregier, Anton, 1965-1973 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Reisman, Philip, 1973-1979; 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Riddle, John, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Robertson, Ron, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - [Rockmore?], undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Rockwell, Norman, 1982-1990 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Rose, David, 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Rossman, Ruth, 1961-1968 (Box 5, Folder 15-16)
  - Russ, Ray, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Russian Icons, 1997; 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 18-19)
  - Russin, Robert, 1964-1988 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Russin, Robert, Prices, 1964-1988 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Santens, James, 1984-1991 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Sardisco, Frank, circa 1963-1983 (Box 5, Folder 23-25)
  - Schnabel, David, 1959-1980 (Box 5, Folder 26-27)
    Oversized material housed in Box 16, Folder 3
  - Schwarz, Gladys, 1974-1981 (Box 5, Folder 28-29)
  - Serisawa, Sueo, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Serl, Jon, 1981-1989 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Shahn, Ben, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Shalom of Safed, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Sherman, Charlotte, 1963-1983 (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
  - Sherman, Charlotte, Prices, circa 1968-1981 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Sicner, James, 1966-1983 (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
  - Sicner, James, Payments, 1967-1976 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Simcock, Jack, 1957-1966 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Siqueiros, David Alfaro, 1971-1995; 1950 (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
  - Sloan, John, 1974-1979 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Smith, June, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Soyer, Moses and Raphael, 1962-1999 (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
  - Sternberg, Harry, circa 1963-1966 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Strindberg, August, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Susman, Malcolm, 1987-1991 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Tana, Andrea, 1992-1996; 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 19-20)
  - Tanner, Henry Ossawa, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Tobey, Mark, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Toth, Andre de, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Ulansey, Vicki, 1980-1982 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Vaughan, Abby, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Villarreal, Andy, 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Weakland, Anna Wu, 1971; 1973 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Weber, Max, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Wein, Albert, 1960s-1970 (Box 6, Folder 29-30)
  - White, Charles (Box 6)
    - Archives of American Art, 1975-1989 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Background Information, 1950s-1983 (Box 6, Folder 32-35)
  - White, Charles (Box 7)
    - Background Information, School Report Cards [photocopies], circa 1980s (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Book Reprint Information, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - California African American Museum, 1981-1989 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - China, 1980-1986 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Collectors Plates, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence (1965-1979), 1963-1979 (Box 7, Folder 6-25)
  - White, Charles (Box 8)
    - Correspondence (1980-1995), 1978-1995 (Box 8, Folder 1-13)
    - Correspondence, [Inquiries], 1980-1986 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence to Frances White, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - District 1199 Cultural Center, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Drawing Show, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Essays About White, 1967-1980 (Box 8, Folder 18-19)
    - "Freedomways", 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - German Exhibition, 1982-1991 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Germany, 1973-1986 (Box 8, Folder 22-25)
    - Hand Graphics, Ltd., 1977-1979; circa 1987 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - The High Museum of Art, 1970; 1975-1978 (Box 8, Folder 27-28)
    - Images of Dignity, 1966-1972 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - White, Charles (Box 9)
    - Images of Dignity, 1966-1980 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    - Inventory Cards and Lists, 1960s-1980 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Inventory Lists, 1978-1980; undated (Box 9, Folder 4-5)
    - "Legends" Exhibition, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Los Angeles Municipal Art Gallery, 1975-1977 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Los Angeles Unified School District of Los Angeles County, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1967; 1979-1981 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Murals, 1974-circa 1982 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Murals Lost, 1972-circa 1982 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Museums, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Musilog, circa 1977 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Obituaries and Memorials, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - "Pages From the Sketchbook" Exhibition (Feb. 6-28, 1987) (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Park Dedication, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Permissions to Reproduce, 1964-1996 (Box 9, Folder 18-19)
    - Photograph, circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Price Lists, 1970-1993 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Print Sales, Hand Graphics, Ltd., 1984 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Printed Materials, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Printed Materials, 1960s (Box 9, Folder 24-28)
      Oversized material housed in Box 16, Folders 4-5
    - Printed Materials, 1970s (Box 9, Folder 29-30)
  - White, Charles (Box 10)
    - Printed Materials, 1970s (Box 10, Folder 1-4)
      Oversized material housed in Box 16, Folders 6-7
    - Printed Materials, 1980s (Box 10, Folder 5-14)
      Oversized material housed in Box 16, Folder 8 and OV 17
    - Printed Materials, 1990s (Box 10, Folder 15-16)
    - Printed Materials, undated (Box 10, Folder 17-19)
    - Speeches, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Statements and Quotes, undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - White, Charles (Box 11)
    - The Studio Museum in Harlem, 1979-1984 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The Studio Museum in Harlem, Material for Catalog, 1970s-1980s (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Title Cell, circa 1960s (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Oversized material housed in Box 16, Folder 9
    - Traveling Shows, 1966-1993 (Box 11, Folder 4-12)
    - Travels, 1974-1977 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Travels, Correspondence, 1973-1977 (Box 11, Folder 14-15)
    - University of California Santa Cruz, 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Frances White, Account, 1984-1989 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Frances White, Book Signings, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Frances White, Correspondence, 1980s (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Frances White, Inventory of Works, 1991-1992; undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Writings by Bill Cosby, circa 1974 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Writings by Benjamin Horowitz, after 1979; 1966 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - White, Ian, 1986-2000 (Box 11, Folder 23-24)
  - Wiener, Leigh, circa 1987 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Wolford, Richard, 1966-1968 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Wyatt, Richard, Jr., 1980-1983 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Wyeth, Andrew, 1983-1986 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Young, Myla, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Zaslove, Alan, 1966-1970 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Zimmerman, Marc, 1986-1989 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Various Artists, Biographical Information, undated; 1960-1994 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Various Artists, Black Artists, 1979-1997 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Various Artists, Black Artists - Zimbabwe, 1980s-1990s (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Restricted Folder (Box 15)
  - Barnes, Ernie, Oversized Material, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    Oversized material from Box 1, Folder 5
  - Hueter, James, Oversized Material, 1960s (Box 16, Folder 2)
    Oversized material from Box 3, Folder 9
  - Schnabel, David, Oversized Material, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    Oversized material from Box 5, Folder 27
  - White, Charles, Oversized Printed Materials, 1960s (Box 16, Folder 4-5)
    Oversized materials from Box 9, Folder 28
  - White, Charles, Oversized Printed Materials, 1970s (Box 16, Folder 6-7)
    Oversized material from Box 10, Folder 1
  - White, Charles, Oversized Printed Materials, 1980s (Box 16, Folder 8)
    Oversized material from Box 10, Folder 5
  - White, Charles, Oversized Title Cell, circa 1960s (Box 16, Folder 9)
    Oversized material from Box 11, Folder 3
  - White, Charles, Oversized Printed Materials, Posters, 1981-1984 (Box OV 17)
- Business Correspondence and Records, 1945-1997; Series 2; 1.6 Linear feet Boxes 12-13
  This series contains incoming and outgoing correspondence with clients and galleries primarily regarding artwork sales, consignments and exhibition loans, the bulk of which is filed as Benjamin Horowitz’s "My Files." Also found is a folder of contracts, many with artists and lithographers, biographical information about Benjamin Horowitz, and other day-to-day business records.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Anderson, Harry "Hunk", 1977-1986 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - "Art of Love" Exhibition, Riverside Art Museum, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Artes de Mexico, 1990-1991 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Casarini, Eilene, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Certificates of Appreciation, 1990s (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Contracts, 1961-1981 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Cornish, Joel, Mrs., 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence ("My Files"), 1962-1989 (Box 12, Folder 11-24)
  - Correspondence ("My Files"), 1990-1996; 1978 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Cosby, Bill, 1972-1978 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Donations, 1969-1973 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Forum Gallery, 1964-1980 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Frame Masters, 1980; 1986 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Galerie du Jonelle, 1966-1972 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Horowitz, Benjamin, 1987-1995 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Horowitz, Benjamin, Biographical Information, 1945-1952 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Jack Glenn Gallery, 1973-1974 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Judah L. Magnes Museum, 1995-1996 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Kebede, Alitash, Matisse, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Kluge, John, 1982-1986; 1997 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Koreans, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Kormind, Henry, 1981-1988 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Manchel, Henrietta, Art Collection, 1981-1990 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Matombo Gallery, Roy Cook, 1987-1988 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Nall, Lillian, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Palmer, Herbert, 1976-1977 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - The Pasadena Conference of Afro-American Artists (Jan. 17, 1987), 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Petteys, Chris, Female Artists, 1976-1978 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - The Piccadilly Gallery, 1965-1966 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Reed, O.P., Jr., 1968-1977 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Russia, 1971-1976 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Ruth S. Schaffner Gallery, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Smith, Chadwick, M.D., 1981-1991 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Spark, Victor, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Trumbo, Dalton, 1965-1977 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Wesson, Barbara, 1985; 1993 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Westside Jewish Community Center, 1965-1968 (Box 13, Folder 29)
- Printed Material, 1960s-1990s; Series 3; 0.6 Linear feet Boxes 13-14, 16
  Printed Material documents exhibitions held at Heritage Gallery through exhibition announcement, catalogs, clippings, and posters. Also found are a handful of printed materials for exhibitions of Heritage Gallery artists held at other galleries and museums.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Book, Nippon Gendai Kogei Bijutsu 1979 [Contemporary Japanese Arts and Crafts] (Box 13, Folder 30)
    Oversized material housed in Box 16, Folder 10
  - Booklet, Art Dealers Association of Southern California, after 1970 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Clippings, 1963-1978 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1960s-1990s, undated (Box 13, Folder 33-37)
  - Exhibition Announcements, Other Galleries and Museums, 1960s-1980s (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1960s-1970s (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1980s-1990s (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Other Galleries and Museums, 1960s-1990s (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Flyer, Plaza de la Raza, Inc., circa 1970 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1973-1983 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Portfolio, "Black Artists in America", 1972 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Oversized material housed in Box 16, Folder 11
  - Posters, 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Oversized Book, Nippon Gendai Kogei Bijutsu 1979 [Contemporary Japanese Arts and Crafts] (Box 16, Folder 10)
    Oversized material from Box 13, Folder 30
  - Oversized Portfolio, "Black Artists in America", 1972 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    Oversized material from Box 14, Folder 5